Register of the Gleb Struve Papers 1810-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL, 1923-1985 (Boxes 23-45, 184)
  - Panina, Issa, 1973-1976. Includes letters of Dimitrii Panin (Folder 13)
  - Pares, Sir Bernard, 1926-1944. Includes correspondence of others (Folder 14)
  - Parker, William, 1944-1952 (Folder 15)
  - Pavlova, Tat'iana
    - 1961-1980 (Folder 16)
    - 1981-1984 (Folder 17)
  - Penguin Books Limited, 1939-1968 (Folder 18)
  - Pensee Russe, 1975-1982 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Petr Fedorovich, surname unknown, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Pichois, Claude, 1952-1972 (Folder 3)
  - Pike, David, 1975-1982 (Folder 4)
  - Pipes, Richard
    - 1958-1968 (Folder 5)
    - 1969-1972 (Folder 6)
    - 1974-1982 (Folder 7)
  - Pollak, Severin, 1963-1982 (Folder 8)
  - Poltoratskii, Nikolai
    - 1955-1965 (Folder 9)
    - 1966-1973 (Folder 10)
    - 1974-1984 (Folder 11)
  - Possev. See Possev Druckerei & Verlag
  - Possev Druckerei & Verlag, 1950-1983 (Folder 12)
  - Preuves, 1953-1963 (Folder 13)
  - Princeton University Press, 1961-1981 (Folder 14)
  - Proyart de Baillescourt, Comtesse Jacqueline de, 1960-1978 (Folder 15)
  - Random House Inc., Alfred Knopf Inc., 1963-1983 (Folder 16)
  - Reve, Karel van het, 1955-1969 (Folder 17)
  - Ricerche Slavistiche, 1961-1973 (Folder 18)
  - Rittenberg, S.A., 1970-1975 (Folder 19)
  - Rowland, Paul, 1963-1967 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Rudinskii, Vladimir, 1976-1977 (Folder 2)
  - Russian Language Journal, 1978-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Russian Review, 1952-1979 (Folder 4)
  - Russica Publishers, Inc. See Sumerkin, A.
  - Rybin, Konstantin, 1954-1981 (Folder 5)
  - Rzhevskii, Leonid, 1952-1984 (Folder 6)
  - Sablin, Evgenii
    - 1924-1931 (Folder 7)
    - 1932-1948 (Folder 8)
  - Sagovskaia, Nina, 1944-1984 (Folder 9)
  - Sagovskii, Roman
    - 1937-1947 (Folder 10)
    - 1948-1974 (Folder 11)
  - Salatko-Petryshche, Valerii. See Pereleshin,Valerii
  - Schapiro, Leonard, 1956-1981 (Folder 12)
  - Schnack, Ingeborg, 1975-1981 (Folder 13)
  - Sechkarev, Vsevolod, 1948-1971 (Folder 14)
  - Semenov-Tian-Shanskii, Bishop Aleksandr, 1922-1976 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Shakhovskaia, Zinaida, 1931-1984 (Folder 2)
  - Shein, A. 1966 (Folder 3)
  - Shklovskaia, Zinaida, 1936-1945 (Folder 4)
  - Shor, Olga, 1957-1983 (Folder 5)
  - Shtromas, Alexander, 1974-1979 (Folder 6)
  - Silver Age Publishing, 1980-1982 (Folder 7)
  - Simmons, Ernest, 1961 (Folder 8)
  - Slavic and East European Journal, 1957-1975 (Folder 9)
  - Slavic Review
    - 1948-1969 (Folder 10)
    - 1970-1972 (Folder 11)
    - 1973-1980 (Folder 12)
  - Smernoff, Susan, 1975-1976 (Folder 13)
  - Smith, Gerald
    - 1973-1978 (Folder 14)
    - 1979-1982 (Folder 15)
  - Smith, Jennifer, 1968-1970 (Folder 16)
  - Sommer, Erich, 1965-1977 (Folder 17)
  - Souvarine, Boris, 1966-1979 (Folder 18)
  - Stammler, Heinrich, 1958-1978 (Folder 19)
  - Stavrou, Theofanis, 1967-1968 (Folder 20)
  - Strakhovskii, Leonid, 1924-1963 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Struve, Aleksei
    - 1921-1929 (Folder 2)
    - 1930-1935 (Folder 3)
    - 1935-1937 (Folder 4)
    - 1938 (Folder 5)
    - 1939 (Folder 6)
    - 1940-1943 (Folder 7)
    - 1944-1945 (Folder 8)
    - 1946 (Folder 9)
    - 1947-1949 (Folder 10)
    - 1950 (Folder 11)
    - 1951 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - 1952 (Folder 2)
    - 1953-1954 (Folder 3)
    - 1955-1958 (Folder 4)
    - 1959-1962 (Folder 5)
    - 1962-1964 (Folder 6)
    - 1965-1968 (Folder 7)
    - 1969 (Folder 8)
    - 1970 (Folder 9)
    - 1971 (Folder 10)
    - 1972 (Folder 11)
    - 1973 (Folder 12)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - 1946-1947, correspondence of Aleksei Struve family with Gleb Struve (Folder 2)
    - 1949-1950, correspondence between Aleksei Struve and Mary Struve (Folder 3)
  - Struve, Arkadii
    - 1920-1946 (Folder 4)
    - 1947-1951 (Folder 5)
  - Struve, Iuliia, 1929 (Folder 6)
  - Struve, Konstantin (Hieromonk Savva)
    - 1924-1927 (Folder 7)
    - 1927-1939 (Folder 8)
  - Struve, Nikita
    - 1952-1961 (Folder 9)
    - 1962-1968 (Folder 10)
    - 1969-1972 (Folder 11)
    - 1973-1978 (Folder 12)
    - 1979-1985 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Struve, Nina
    - 1922-1923 (Folder 2)
    - 1924 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1925 (Folder 5)
    - 1926 (Folder 6)
    - 1927 (Folder 7)
    - 1928 (Folder 8)
    - 1929 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 1930 (Folder 2)
    - 1931 (Folder 3)
    - 1932 (Folder 4-5)
    - 1933 (Folder 6)
    - 1934 (Folder 7)
    - 1935 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 1936 (Folder 2)
    - 1937 (Folder 3)
    - 1938 (Folder 4)
    - 1939 (Folder 5)
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 6)
    - Iuliia Struve, 1922-1929, 1930-1938 (Folder 7)
    - Grandchildren, 1923-1941 (Folder 8)
    - Fragments, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Struve, Petr, 1923-1938 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Studies in Romanticism, 1961-1983 (Folder 2)
  - Sumerkin, A., 1979-1984 (Folder 3)
  - Survey, 1957-1964 (Folder 4)
  - Taranovskii, Kirill
    - 1956-1967 (Folder 5)
    - 1968-1970 (Folder 6)
    - 1971-1973 (Folder 7)
    - 1974-1979 (Folder 8)
  - Tatarinova, R. A., 1923-1945 (Folder 9)
  - Terras, Victor, 1975-1978 (Folder 10)
  - Thomson, David
    - 1962-1971 (Folder 11)
    - 1972-1985 (Folder 12)
  - Time, 1951-1981 (Folder 13)
  - Times (London), 1933-1980 (Folder 14)
  - Toporkov, Iurii, 1965-1969 (Folder 15)
  - Tsetlin, Mikhail, 1927-1945 (Folder 16)
  - Tyrkova-Williams, Ariadna, 1920-1960 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Unbegaun, Boris, 1937-1970 (Folder 2)
  - Unbegaun Festschrift Committee, 1967-1968 (Folder 3)
  - United States Information Agency, 1955-1961 (Folder 4)
  - University of California Press, 1961-1979 (Folder 5)
  - Vecherin, Evgenii, 1952-1966 (Folder 6)
  - Vernadsky, George, 1950-1973 (Folder 7)
  - Virginia Historical Society, 1948-1949 (Folder 8)
  - Voitsekhovskii, Sergei, 1969-1979 (Folder 9)
  - Vodov, Sergei, 1954-1968 (Folder 10)
  - Vol'skaia-Valentinova, Valentina, 1967-1970 (Folder 11)
  - Volkov, Boris, 1949-1954 (Folder 12)
  - Walpole, Sir Hugh, 1931 (Folder 13)
  - Wat, Alexander, 1962-1966 (Folder 14)
  - Webb, Sidney, 1935 (Folder 15)
  - West, Dr. (?), 1964-1966 (Folder 16)
  - Whitfield, Frank, 1957-1985 (Folder 17)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1947-1962 (Folder 18)
  - Wilson, Elena, 1958-1979 (Folder 19)
  - Wisconsin Studies in Contemporary Literature, 1965-1967 (Folder 20)
  - Wolfe, Bertram, 1959-1969 (Folder 21)
  - Wytrzens, Gunther, 1958-1974 (Folder 22)
  - Yakobson, Sergius, 1936-1979 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Yale Review, 1948-1954 (Folder 2)
  - Y.M.C.A. Press, 1970-1976 (Folder 3)
  - Yarmolinskii, Avrahm, 1962-1967 (Folder 4)
  - Yearbook of Comparative and General Literature, 1954-1965 (Folder 5)
  - Zhirmunskii, V., n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Zubov, Valentin, 1956-1959 (Folder 7)
  - Zuckermann, Alexandra
    - 1972-1973 (Folder 8)
    - 1974-1975 (Folder 9)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, ARRANGED BY SUBJECT, 1916-1982 (Boxes 45-56)
  Notes, drafts, typescript copies and printed copies of books, articles, lectures, translations, book reviews, letters to the editor and radio broadcasts by Gleb Struve.
  - Adamovich, Georgii
    - "G. Adamovich, kritik", Russkaia Mysl', typescript copy, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "O g-ne Adamoviche, Gumileve i prochem", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoe Slovo, typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - "Sumerki Bloka ili sem' piatnits na nedele g-na Adamovicha", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo (?), handwritten draft, (?), n.d. (Folder 12)
    - Adamovich, Georgii (Contd.)
    - "Po povodu stat'i G. Adamovicha", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Jan. 7, 1951. (Folder 13)
    - "Ob Adamoviche-kritike", Grani, No. 34-35, April-Sept. 1957, printed copy. See scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 14)
    - "G. V. Adamovich i 'Doktor Zhivago'", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, July 6, 1959, printed copy (Folder 15)
  - Akhmatova, Anna
    - "Kak byl vpervye izdan 'Rekviem'. Spravka dlia potomstva", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 16)
    - "O pervom izdanii 'Rekviema' Akhmatovoi", typescript, n.d. (Folder 17)
    - Anna Akhmatova. Sochineniia, Inter-Language Literary Associates, 1965
      - Introduction and frontispiece, vol.I, proof copy, 1965 (Folder 18)
      - "Akhmatova i Boris Anrep", typescript draft and proof copy (Folder 19)
      - "Akhmatova i Nedobrovo", typescript drafts, proof copy and miscellaneous material (Folder 20-21)
      - "Dopolneniia, utochneniia i ispravleniia k bibliografii Akhmatovoi", appendix to collected works, typescript (Folder 22)
      - "Iz leningradskikh elegii", typescript draft (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - "Primechaniia k pis'mam", galley proof (Folder 2)
      - "Stikhi raznykh let"
        - Typescript draft (Folder 3)
        - Proof copy (Folder 4)
      - Notes and miscellaneous material
        - Typescript (Folder 5)
        - Handwritten (Folder 6)
      - Reviews (Folder 7)
        - Akhmatova, Anna, critical review of Sobranie sochinenii, photocopy of published article, 1960
        - Anna Akhmatova. Sochineniia, reviews, 1969, printed copies
        - Sobranie sochinenii Anny Akhmatovoi, t. III, clippings, 1983
    - Anna Akhmatova, sochineniia, dopolnitel'nyi vypusk
      - Frontispiece and typescript draft (Folder 8)
      - Correspondence between Boris Filippov and Nikita Struve, 1974-1977 (Folder 9)
    - "Iz besed s A. A. Akhmatovoi, (Iun' 1965)", typescript draft, 1965 (?) (Folder 10)
    - "Iosif Brodskii-Anne Akmatovoi", Russkaia Mysl', Feb. 20, 1965, printed copy (Folder 11)
    - "Stikhotvorenie E. M. Tager ob Anne Akhmatovoi", Russkaia Mysl', Oct. 7, 1965, printed copy (Folder 12)
    - "Dva 'neizvestnykh' stikhotvoreniia Anny Akhmatovoi", Russkaia Mysl', Jan. 10, 1967, printed copy (Folder 13)
    - Lecture about Anna Akhmatova, delivered at the Frederick Burke School Auditorium, March 10, 1967, typescript copy (Folder 14)
    - Rekviem, "Tovareshchistvo Zarubezhnykh Pisatelei" edition, review by Iu. Terapiano, unidentified newspaper, printed copy, n.d. (Folder 15)
    - "Novye izdaniia Akhmatovoi", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Oct. 14, 1976, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 16)
  - Aldanov, Mark. Review of C. Nicholas Lee, The Novels of Mark Aleksandrovic Aldanov, Slavic Review, March 1971, printed copy (Folder 17)
  - Andreev, Nikolai. "K konchine N. E. Andreeva", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Andronikova-Halpern, Salomeia (Folder 19)
    - "Pamiati S. N. Gal'pern", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, June 27, 1982, printed copy. Includes printed copy of same article in Russkaia Mysl', July 1, 1982
    - "Eshche k konchine S. N. Andronikovoi-Gal'pern", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, July 25, 1982, printed copy. Includes printed copy of same article in Russkaia Mysl', Aug. 19, 1982
  - Anrep, Boris von
    - "B. V. Anrep", Russkaia Mysl', April 26, 1969, printed copy (Folder 20)
    - "K konchine U. P. von Anrep", (wife of B. Anrep), Novoye Russkoe Slovo, March 18, 1973. Obituary, printed copy
  - Babel', Isaak
    - "Babel', Slonim i Zoshchenko", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 21)
    - Untitled writing, n.d. Relates to Isaac Babel's play Zakat, typescript copy (Folder 22)
  - Bal'mont, Konstantin
    - "Bal'mont--pevets Rossii", review of K. D. Bal'mont, V razdvinutoi dali. Poema o Rossii, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, March 29, 1930, printed copy (Folder 23)
    - "O familii Bal'monta", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, June, 19, 1977, printed copy (Folder 24)
    - "Eshche o Bal'monte-Bal'monte", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Jan. 1978, printed copy (Folder 25)
  - Baratynskii, Evgenii
    - "Evgeny Baratynsky", The Slavonic and East European Review, Jan. 1945, printed copy (Folder 26)
    - "Baratynskii", Novyi Zhurnal, 1948, printed copy (Folder 27)
  - Belinkov, Arkadii. Untitled obituary of Arkadii Belinkov, typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 28)
  - Belyi, Andrei
    - "K biografii Andreia Belogo", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 29)
    - "Surrealisme Avant La Lettre", review of Andrei Belyi, St. Petersburg, translated by John Cournos, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 30)
    - Untitled writing, n.d. Relates to Andrei Belyi, typescript (Folder 31)
    - "Andrej Belyj's Experiments With Novel Technique", lecture delivered at the VII International Congress of Modern Languages and Literatures in Heidelberg, typescript, printed copy and miscellaneous handwritten notes, 1957 (?) (Folder 32)
    - "A Pioneer of the Modern Novel", review of Andrei Belyi St. Petersburg, translated by John Cournos, The New Leader, Oct. 5, 1959, printed copy (Folder 33)
    - "K biografii Andreiia Belogo. A. Belyi i A. A. Turgenev", Annali dell'Istituto Universitario Orientale, XIII, 1970, offprint (Folder 34)
    - "Andrei Belyi Redivivus", keynote lecture delivered at the International Symposium on Andrei Belyi, the University of Kentucky, Lexington, March 27-29, 1975 (Folder 35)
      - Miscellaneous material re conference. Includes program and lectures by other speakers, typescript copies (Folder 36)
      - Correspondence, University of Kentucky re publication of Belyi Symposium (Folder 37)
      - Anthology (Life and Works of Andrei Belyi, Gerald Janacek, ed.), 1976-1977
    - "Andrei Belyi Redivivus", Russkaia Mysl', April 10, 1975, printed copy (Folder 38)
    - "Simposium ob Andree Belom", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, April 17, 1975 (Folder 39)
    - "K biografii Andreiia Belogo: tri dokumenta", Novyi Zhurnal, Sept. 1976, printed copy (Folder 40)
  - Berberova, Nina. Review of Nina Berberova, The Italics Are Mine, The Russian Review, Jan. 1970, miscellaneous notes and printed copy (Folder 41)
  - Berdiaev, Nikolai. "P. B. Struve i N. A. Berdiaev", Russkaia Mysl', Nov. 30, 1967, printed copy (Folder 42)
  - Blok, Aleksandr
    - "Aleksandr Blok. K piatiletiiu smerti", Vozrozhdenie, Aug. 8, 1926, printed copy. See scrapbook of printed articles 1926-1932 (Folder 43)
    - "Magiia Bloka", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Aug. 10, 1931. See scrapbook 1926-1932 (Folder 44)
    - "The Puppet Show", translation into English (with Mary Kriger), Slavonic and East European Review, April, 1950, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 45)
    - "Eshche o 'Dvenadtsati' Bloka", Russkaia Mysl', Jan. 30, 1962, printed copy (Folder 46)
    - "Aleksandr Blok i pervaia mirovaia voina", Nov. 2, 1965, printed copy (Folder 47)
    - "Otreksia li Blok ot 'Dvenadtsati'?", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Sept. 8, 1974. Includes letter to the editor in answer to reaction to his article, printed copies (Folder 48)
  - Bogatyrev, Konstantin
    - "Pamiati K. Bogatyreva", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, July 11, 1976. Obituary, printed copy (Folder 49)
    - "O Konstantine Bagatyreve", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, May 9, 1982, printed copy (Folder 50)
  - Briusov, Valerii. "Ob odnom stikhotvorenii Valeriia Briusova", typescript, n.d. (Folder 51)
  - Brodsky, Iosif
    - "O poete-'tuneiadtse'Iosife Brodskom", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 52)
    - "Koe-chto ob Iosife Brodskom", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, April 22, 1973, printed copy (Folder 53)
    - "Brodsky's Poetry", New York Review of Books, July 19, 1973. Letter to the editor, relates to George Kline's article about Joseph Brodsky, typescript draft and printed copy (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Bunin, Ivan
    - "I. A. Bunin i P. B. Struve", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 2)
    - "The New Nobel Laureate: Ivan Bunin", typescript copy, n.d. Also includes German translation (Folder 3)
    - "O tom kak I. A. Bunin porval znakomstvo so mnoi", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Review of Woodward study of Ivan Bunin, typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 5)
    - "L'amour de la vie et le sens de la mort dans l'oeuvre d'Ivan Bunine", Le Mois, Dec. 1931-Jan. 1932, printed copy (Folder 6)
    - "Tvorchestvo Bunina", Dec. 1, 1933, lecture (?), typescript and printed copy (Folder 7)
    - "Ivan Bunin", review of Ivan Bunin: The Gentleman from San Francisco, and Other Stories, trans. by D. H. Lawrence, S. S. Kotelianskii, and Leonard Woolf, The Observer, Feb. 25, 1934, printed copy (Folder 8)
    - "Bunin v sovetskoi kritike", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Jan. 3, 1954, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 9)
    - "K. Paustovskii o Bunine", Russkaia Mysl', July 17, 1962, printed copy (Folder 10)
    - "Iz perepiski s I. A. Buninym", Annali dell'Istituto Universitario Orientale, 1968, reprint (Folder 11)
    - "Eshche o Bunine i Bogomolove", letter to the editor, Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Sept. 6, 1973, printed copy (Folder 12)
    - Review of V. G. Bazanov et al., eds., Literaturnoe nasledstvo. Vol. 84: Ivan Bunin, Slavic Review, Sept. 1975, typescript and proof copy (Folder 13)
    - "Novaia kniga o Bunine", Russkaia Mysl', Nov. 11, 1979. Review of A.V. Bakhrakh's memoirs about Bunin, printed copy (Folder 14)
  - Chaianov, Aleksandr. See Ivan Kremnev
  - Chekhov, Anton
    - Untitled writing, typescript, n.d. (Folder 15)
    - "Anton Chekhov: His Life and Work", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 16)
    - "Chekhov, Meyerhold i sovetskie fal'sifikatory", Grani, No. 22, 1954, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 17)
    - "Chekhov v partiinoi tsenzure", typescript draft, 1954 (?) (Folder 18)
    - "Tchekhov deux fois censure", Preuves, No. 43, Sept. 1954, printed copy (Folder 19)
    - "Chekhov and Soviet Doublethink", The New Leader, Nov. 22, 1954, printed copy (Folder 20)
    - "Chekhov v sovetskoi tsenzure", Novyi Zhurnal, No. 37, 1954, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 21)
    - "Chekhov in Communist Censorship", The Slavonic and East European Review, Vol. XXXIII, No. 81, June 1955, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 22)
    - "Chekhov i Grigorovich", chapter from T. Eekman, ed., Anton Cechov, 1860-1960. Some Essays, 1960, author's corrected copy and reprint (Folder 23)
    - "On Chekhov's Craftsmanship: the Anatomy of a Story", The Slavic Review, Oct., 1961, galley proof and printed copy (Folder 24)
    - Review of Ernest J. Simmons, Chekhov: A Biography, Slavic Review, Sept. 1962, printed copy (Folder 25)
  - Dostoevsky, Fedor
    - Broadcast for Radiostantsiia Osvobozhdenie, "Obrashchenie professora G. P. Struve v sviazi s 75 letiem so dnia smerti F. M. Dostoevskogo", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 26)
    - Untitled writing, n.d. Relates to the fiftieth anniversary of Dostoevsky's death, typescript copy (Folder 27)
    - "Ob odnom zabytom tolkovateli Dostoevskogo", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Aug. 1971, printed copy (Folder 28)
    - "Zametki o iazyke Dostoevskogo", printed copy of paper delivered at the Third International Dostoevskii Symposium in Runstedgorde, Denmark, 1977 (Folder 29)
      - Program (Folder 30)
      - Papers delivered by other participants in the symposium, typescript copies, n.d. (Folder 31)
    - "Ob odnom slove Dostoevskogo", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, June 24, 1980 and Russkaia Mysl', July 17, 1980, typescripts and printed copy (Folder 32)
    - "Koe -chto o iazyke Dostoevskogo: upotreblenie Dostoevskim zaimstvovannykh slov i zloupotreblenie imi", typescript draft for paper delivered at Fourth International Dostoevsky Symposium, Bergamo, Aug. 17-23, 1980 (Folder 33)
      - Typescript and handwritten notes, n.d. (Folder 34)
      - Miscellaneous material. Includes business correspondence with organizers, 1979-1980 (Folder 35)
  - Ehrenburg, Il'ia
    - Untitled writing, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 36)
    - "O poslednem romane Ehrenburga", Russkaia Mysl', July 25, 1952, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 37)
  - Esenin, Sergei. "The Hero of Imagism", The Times Literary Supplement, Dec. 17, 1976, printed copy. Includes typescript draft entitled "Esenin and His Legend" (Folder 38)
  - Frank, Semen
    - "S. L. Frank i P. B. Struve: glavnye etapy ikh druzhby", Sbornik pamiati Semena Liudvigovicha Franka. 1877-1950, 1954, printed copy (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Sbornik pamiati S. L. Franka, order forms, 1954, typescript (Folder 2)
    - "S. L. Frank. K stoletiiu so dnia rozhdeniia", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Jan. 1, 1977, notes, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 3)
  - Gippius, Zinaida
    - "Ob odnom stikhotvorenii Zinaidy Gippius", Russkaia Mysl', June 15, 1972, typescript and printed copy (Folder 4)
    - "Iz perepiski Z. N. Gippius s M. L. Kantorom (1927-1936)", Novyi Zhurnal, Sept. 1973, printed copy (Folder 5)
  - Gumilev, Nikolai
    - "Gumilev", typescript draft for public lecture (?), n.d. (Folder 6)
    - "Iz arkhiva N. S. Gumileva. Neizdannye materialy dlia biografii Gumileva i istorii literaturnykh techenii", tearsheets pp. 181-187 (Folder 7)
    - "Iz 'Zapisok kavalerista' N. Gumileva", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 8)
    - "The Joyful Brotherhood", translation of "Veselye brat'ia", typescript drafts, n.d. (Folder 9)
    - "K shestidesiatiletiiu rasstrela N. S. Gumileva, ob odnom znakomstve Gumileva", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 10)
    - "N. S. Gumilev v pis'makh M. F. Larionova i B. A. Anrepa", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - "O vremeni napisaniia 'Gondly' N. S. Gumileva", letter to the editor of Novyi Zhurnal, typescript, n.d. (Folder 12)
    - "Gumilev", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Aug. 29, 1931, printed copy (Folder 13)
    - "Neizdannye stikhi N. Gumileva", Novyi Zhurnal, 1944, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 14)
    - "Pamiati Gumileva", Russkii Zhurnal (?), Jan. 2, 1947, printed copy (Folder 15)
    - "Materialy dlia biografii N. S. Gumileva po neizdannym dokumentam", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Dec. 16, 1947, printed copy (Folder 16)
    - "Ob 'Otravlennoi Tunike' Gumileva", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Dec. 10, 1950, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1955 (Folder 17)
    - Neizdannyi Gumilev
      - Correspondence, Chekhov Publishing House, 1952 (Folder 18)
      - Book reviews, 1952, printed copies (Folder 19)
    - "Ob odnom stikhotvorenii Gumileva", Russkaia Mysl', July 5, 1960, printed copy (Folder 20)
    - N. Gumilev. Sobranie sochinenii, Boris Filippov and Gleb Struve eds., 1962-1965
      - "N. S. Gumilev. Zhizn' i lichnost'", tearsheets with commentary, n.d. (Folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous material re Gumilev. Includes handwritten notes and typescript drafts, n.d. (Folder 22-24)
      - Correspondence, I. Baschkirtzew Buchdruckerei, 1962-1975 (Folder 25)
      - Publication agreement, Victor Kamkin, Gleb Struve and Boris Filippov, 1965 (Folder 26)
      - Reviews and publisher's announcements, printed copies, 1962-1966 (Folder 27)
    - "Innokentii Annenskii i Gumilev", Novyi Zhurnal, Bk. 78, March 1965, tearsheets (Folder 28)
    - "Gumilev v 'Literaturnoi Gazete'", Russkai Mysl' (?), 1967 (?), printed copy (Folder 29)
    - "Sovetskii poet o Gumileve", Russkai Mysl', March 18, 1967, printed copy (Folder 30)
    - "Eshche o Tat'iane Gnedich i ee 'Venke sonetov'", Russkaia Mysl', March 25, 1967 (Folder 31)
    - "Neizvestnyii i maloizvestnyii Gumilev", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, July 22, 1971, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 32)
    - "O Gumileve v Abyssinii", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Dec. 5, 1975, letter to the editor, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 33)
    - N. S. Gumilev. Neizdannye stikhi i pis'ma, 1980
      - Reviews, typescript and printed copies, 1980 (Folder 34)
    - "Ob odnom znakomstve Gumileva", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Sept. 1981 (?), printed copy (Folder 35)
    - "K shestidesiatiletiiu so dnia gibeli", Russkaia Mysl', Aug. 27, 1981, printed copy (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "Eshche k shestidesiatiletiiu smerti N. S. Gumileva. Neizvestnoe stikhotvorenie Dm. Klenovskogo", typescript draft, 1981(?) (Folder 2)
  - Ivanov, Georgii
    - "Zametki o stikhakh. Georgii Ivanov. Rozy. Parizh 1931", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Oct. 17, 1931, printed copy. See scrapbook 1926-1932 (Folder 3)
    - "O retsenzii Georgiia Ivanova na 'Sobranie sochinenii' Osipa Mandel'shtama", Novyi Zhurnal, Bk. 45, 1956, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 4)
  - Khodasevich, Vladislav
    - Review of Tiazhelaia lira, Russkaia Mysl', 1923, printed copy (Folder 5)